You
Took you long enough
Finally caught your eye, huh?
Well... I guess there... is something.
I want you to crush Kiriyama's pride in your next Shogi match!
Ah, boy. I was wondering what he was going to say.
That's asking an awful lot.
All right, then.
Guess we should continue.
He urged me to go on. I looked at the board, and quickly came back to my senses.
I can't continue.
That's how bad this really is?
The first thing I felt... was shock. Then I was overcome by a wave of embarrassment. It felt like I was choking on my own shame.
Until just a moment ago... I couldn't see it.
Games against people like that are usually long and drawn out. That's my weakness.
What the hell? People like that?
I can't let it get to me. Or he'll eat me alive.
What am I doing? How could I even think like that?
I totally misread his skill level.
I just wanted to win. So I dragged the game out and waited for him to make a mistake.
And thought of him as nothing more than his ranking.
I can't lose this match. No matter what.
I can't even read the strength of the player in front of me.
And yet I let myself get carried away by a grudge.
I'm up against an A-class player and I treat him like an amateur?
What the hell's wrong with me?
I want to run away. I want to disappear.
I've got to get away from here.
Pitch black. Blinding.
I can't breathe.
Breathe.
I understood the sound of him clearing his throat.
It was a message telling me to calm down.
So as he requested...
With my mind in a state of confusion...
I desperately played on...
As I continued...
I began to realize...
That I had been looking down on him.
The fact is...
I just figured out how wrong I was.
And I felt nervous.
He saw right through it.
He could see it all.
Sitting there quietly like that.
Never saying a word.
If I decided to run away...
Right in the middle of the game because I'm mortified...
It would be wrong.
A selfish move.
And he's an opponent that would know it.
So I fought on.
I found what was left of my will to continue...
And left.
If I decided to run away...
Right in the middle of the game because I'm mortified...
It would be wrong.
A selfish move.
I found what was left of my will to continue...
And kept playing.
But...
Before I had a chance to recover...
It was already over.
And then...
Then, I found what was left of my will to continue, and kept playing.
But, before I had a chance to recover, it was already over.
And then, the post-match review began.
Where'd I go wrong?
Okay.
Why don't we replay from this point in the match?
Rook to 5-8? From there?
He set it up immediately.
So, that move must have been the turning point.
But...
Uh, starting from here?
This early on?
I was already losing this early on?
Okay, what if I went to pawn to 5-4?
Hmm...
Gold 5-4.
Silver 5-4.
Bishop 2-4.
Pawn 2-4.
Then, what if I had done this instead?
Pawn 1-5.
Pawn, same.
Then, silver 3-5?
Silver 3-5.
Bishop 3-5.
And pawn 3-7+.
Lance 1-5.
Pawn 3-4.
Silver 4-2.
What then?
Pawn 1-5.
Pawn 6-5?
Bishop 5-7 promoted.
Silver 5-7.
Bishop 3-7.
No matter what,
I lose.
I'm no match for him.
I appreciate your help, sir.
Thank you.
I was trembling with shame.
I just had to run away from that place.
Everything I did was wrong.
I was...
a total failure.
Ooh.
Would you look at him go?
Oh, hey, Smith.
Here for a match?
Nah, just practice in a bit.
Yis and I were talking about your match.
I feel bad for the kid.
So young.
He's still inexperienced
and didn't know how to read his opponent.
He was blown away.
Must feel like he's lost everything.
I know, I get it.
Irrational youth.
It's humiliating.
Sheesh.
Can you believe it?
That punk only cared to make copies of Mr. Goto's
in your game records before the match.
It sounds like what a kid would do.
Bet he made 20 copies of Goto's
and like only five of mine.
Wait, am I right?
That little brat just keeps pissing me off.
Well, I can't say I haven't done anything like that before myself.
But never anything as obvious as that.
Well, yeah.
Of course.
Everyone has once or twice.
I'd prefer not to remember mine, though.
So, Mr. Goto's next, huh?
Good luck, man.
He's a scary one.
And that face.
Yeah.
Hope I win.
He is scary, though.
You're right.
I want to win so I can go up against Soya for the title.
I'm starving.
Want to grab a bite?
Uh, well, I'm kind of busy.
With what?
A girlfriend?
I wish.
No, not that.
Uh, well, whatever.
Go on, then.
Shoo.
Ah, see you later, then.
And that was a good game today.
Hello?
Kiddo?
How you feeling?
I see.
Yeah, I won all right.
Uh-huh.
Oh, really?
So you were able to watch the match online, huh?
Still, he's an interesting guy.
A real mix of stubbornness and honesty.
I don't know if I really crushed him like you wanted, though.
Yeah, I think I understand.
I get where you're coming from.
Hmm.
Yeah.
You think we should invite him?
To join the workshop?
I'm finally home.
Nice strawberry baby!
I'm sorry Daddy kept you waiting in time for Num-Num.
You're such a cutie pie.
Did you miss your daddy?
Hey!
Yep!
You
When I was awake, I
Couldn't stop thinking about what had happened
So I slept and I slept
The whole time I thought I'd be going up against Goto
So I barely got any sleep
I spent all of my time obsessively going over the game records
Then I crashed, hard
All the sleepless nights without food and water finally caught up with me
But then, I finally couldn't sleep anymore
What is this?
I was completely dehydrated
The symptoms would have gone away if I could only rehydrate
However, I couldn't keep anything I drank down
I was freaking out
Crap
What do I do?
I've gotta get some fluids in me
I forgot most of that night
But I have the faintest memory
Of drinking a sports drink with a pinch of salt
It took most of the day
Just to find the energy to get up
Then
I practically crawled to the neighborhood convenience store
I feel like such an idiot
I can't even do depression right
Retail positions
Office
Programmer
Floor staff
Security
Driver
Kitchen staff
There are so many kinds of jobs
The options are endless
But almost every one of them
Well, yeah
Of course
I don't graduate from high school for two more years
Until then
The only way a student like me can earn enough money to pay the rent
Is by playing shogi
That's all I can do
I'll be missing a lot of school with all of my upcoming matches
I'll be cutting it close
But I have to graduate
That's how I'll eventually be able to choose my own path
That's when I decided to go back to school
Hustle
Take it all the way down the court
Got it
Hustle
No way
P.E.
And basketball
I don't even know how to play
I guess I should run too
So I don't stand out
Hey, you over there
Guy in the glasses, catch
Here it comes
Oh no
Now what do I do
Okay, the net's over there
Should I pass it or go for it
The ball's mine
Aw, you moron
Hey, four eyes
What the hell are you doing?
Good question
Seriously
What the hell am I doing here?
It's no good
I can't even taste anything
It's like eating sand
Is this what it means?
To not run away?
I wanted to have memories of not running away
No more running
What if I was just pretending not to run away this whole time?
Then what do I do?
Who the hell even knows anymore?
Something's different
I'm not the kind of student I imagined I'd be
I thought I'd be able to handle all of this responsibility
It sounds amazing
I thought if I left home
That I would be able to pay the rent
And figure out a way to feed myself
That I would be considered an adult
And as an adult
As an adult
I thought
I wouldn't have to cry
Anymore
Hey, Kiriyama?
What's wrong with you?
Why are you crying?
What the hell is this?
A job magazine?
I don't get it
Why is the student sitting on the stairs all alone
Crying over a job magazine?
There's something messed up about this whole situation
It's not right!
Besides, he's the fifth middle school student to ever become a pro shogi player
He's the rising star of the shogi world
There's so much to dig into here
I don't know where to start
Here, have this
But I...
Never mind, just eat it
Who wants to have a cold lunch when they're totally depressed?
That stuff will kill you
But this will warm you up
Go on, otherwise you'll lose half your hit points
So, Kiriyama
I've been thinking
Why don't you move back to your mentor's house?
Uh...
But... I...
You've got all these matches and rank-deciding competitions to worry about
There are tests to study for in high school and meals to make
You have laundry to do
And you have to deal with whatever else is going on in your life
That's a lot
More than enough for a 17-year-old to handle
Yeah, but...
Face it, it's too much to deal with all by yourself
Hmm...
It's too bad about the Shishio tournament
Saw it online
Shimada Eighth Den
He's one hell of a good player
He came on the scene with Grandmaster Soya
But never managed to stand out
He was even able to make it all the way to A-Class before long
He's proven to be the epitome of ambition
And recently...
He's been a regular at all the title matches
Incredible, huh?
Why do you know so much?
We're both the same age
So I'm curious
I've heard that...
Shimada's really passionate about popularizing Shogi
He even has a special workshop he holds where young players can train with him
What do you think, Rei?
Have you ever thought about something like that?
Joining a workshop?
Well...
No...
I don't know if that's really for me
I think you should try it
Yeah, but the thing is...
I think Shimada's workshop is worth checking out
I'm pretty sure that your friend Nikaido Fourth Dan is also a member there as well
But...
Come on, at least think about it
Being able to learn from the person who beat you could be a huge opportunity
Yeah, but...
Aw, jeez!
That's all you've been saying!
Butt, butt, butt, butt, butt!
If a hundred butts could open a door for you, fine!
But stating the obvious, there ain't no door like that!
Yeah, but...
Don't give me any more damn butts!
I don't get it
Why can't we just reach out to Kiriyama and see what he says?
Weren't you just saying something the other day about inviting him to join the workshop?
I thought it was your idea
Hmm...
It's difficult to explain, but it's not for me to decide
All we can really do right now is wait for him to come to us
So he needs to make the first move?
Yeah
He needs to make the first move
Oh, Kiriyama.
Look at this. It's amazing.
Did they just have an argument?
No way. I've never seen Mr. Shimada like this.
No! That was nothing at all!
Really? It's that embarrassing?
What is this... feeling?
Strawberry will be just as cute in the next March Comes In Like a Lion!
I don't think she's in the next one.
Why not? She's too cute not to be!
Oh, I love you!
And don't like to do it!
Ultimately it is when you run out of breath.
I love you!
Now monsieur she is your friend.
With this belief on Strachofias on April 24.
It signs a lie in divorce.
On April 24.
Let's grab a nice tie either.
Take off one step back.